Alejandro Sánchez Bautista

Freiburg, Germany



hi@alexsanz.dev



+49 176 23551547



linkedin.com/in/alexsanzder



https://www.alexsanz.dev

Summary

10+ years of experience in eCommerce full-stack development and responsive design, including mobile app development and cross-platform solutions (HTML, CSS, JS, GraphQL), as well experience and understanding of UI/UX design principles and process and mobile payments.

Strong communication & collaboration skills with designers and developers teams. Ability working in multicultural and geographically distributed team. Experience in program management and project management. Team collaboration, work under pressure, proactive approach to problem-solving, entrepreneurship, meeting deadlines and improving results. Fast learning ability in emerging technologies.

Specialties:

- eCommerce OXID eSales, Magento and OpenCart.
- Web Design/Development: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, ReactJS, GraphQL & MySQL.
- UX/UI Design: Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop.

Experience

Senior Software Developer Professional Services

OXID eSales AG

Apr 2021 - Present (3 months +)

- Implementation of a modern working environment using the latest technologies and a selection of the best collaboration tools.
- Delivering multiple mobiles and web E-Commerce solutions implementing the OXID framework and GraphQL.
- Applying Agile Methodologies and CI/CD approach as a Professional Scrum Master and taking the advantage of all modern software development best practices.
- E-Commerce Slutions Consultant

Software Developer Professional Services

OXID eSales AG

Apr 2017 - Mar 2021 (4 years)

- A user-centered approach to web design and development ensuring user satisfaction.
- Implementation of OXID eSales shop system delivering well integrated, leading-edge digital solution.
- Develop custom client modules and integration of various third-party services.

MAXCON Full Stack Developer

Naxcon GmbH

Nov 2016 - Apr 2017 (6 months)

Web & Mobile App Development

• UI/UX Design

Mobile App Developer & Technical Lead

Weetsi Solutions

Mar 2014 - May 2016 (2 years 3 months)

- Technical lead mobile applications development.
- UX and UI design for mobile applications.

Software Developer & Technical Lead

CTIN Centro de Tecnología e Innovación

Sep 2012 - Aug 2014 (2 years)

- Technical lead mobile applications development.
- UX and UI design for mobile applications.
- Mobile Developer at Mozilla team for Firefox OS Apps.
- · Active member Mozilla-Mexico, supporting in national events such as the "Congreso Universitario Telcel" and "Congreso Universitario de Tecnologías" and promoting mobile applications development using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript.
- Digital content editor for Sochi Winter Olympics Games 2014 platform.
- Live sport entertainment website content production (highlights clips and media galleries).
- Live schedule management and maintenance.

Mobile Application Developer

Grupo PROMASS

Dec 2011 - Aug 2012 (9 months)

- Internal system architecture design improvement and implementation of REST API.
- · Middleware system development to be used as web service for web and mobile developments.
- UX and UI design and development of cross-platform mobile application for sales team using PhoneGap for iOS devices (iPad).
- Insurance quote WebApp development for sales team applying geolocation and online quotation using web-services.
- Integration of eCommerce and mobile payments.
- Hardware Support and maintenance.
- Online Support (Help Desk).

Front-End Developer

Freelancer

Apr 2009 - Nov 2011 (2 years 8 months)

- Web and WebMobile design for new online business.
- eCommerce consultancy on marketing solutions using 24/7 online stores, online payments and mobile payments.
- Payments migration solutions to mobile devices.
- Analysis, development and implementation of web applications.
- B2B, B2C, C2B, C2C solutions deployment and ERP/CRM integrations.
- Interfaces design and development for new systems.
- Customers recommendations of new technologies implementation feasibility assessment

• Installation of content management systems (CMS) and web hosting.

Web Designer

Freelancer

Jul 2008 - Mar 2009 (9 months)

- Web Design, Graphic Design and Multimedia Design.
- Development and implementation of billing system.
- Management and maintenance of systems for desktop, server operating system (Linux), Apache web servers, print servers (EFI Fyeri).
- Network installation and installation of IP surveillance cameras.
- Support and maintenance (preventive and corrective) to computer equipment and Xerox print servers.

(XX) Internship

Volkswagen de México

Aug 2007 - Jun 2008 (11 months)

- · Analysis and development of the software solution to improve the management and control of special vehicles (prototypes).
- Management of special vehicles in the area of technical development.
- · Control, review and special vehicles shipment.

Education



Tecnológico de Monterrey

Certificate, Computer Software and Media Applications

2012 - 2013

iPhone & Android.



📖 IBERO Puebla

Certificate, Industrial and Product Design

2008 - 2008



Certificate, Industrial Design

2008 - 2008

Instituto Tecnologico Superior de Ciudad Serdan

Bachelor of Science - BS, Industrial Engineering

2005 - 2007

Application Development of new processes, Lean Manufacturing, Project Management, Quality Systems, Managing Budgets.

Sprachenkolleg für ausländische Studierende

B2 Certificate, German Language

2015 - 2016

Academie Linguistique Internationale - ALI

B2 Certificate, English Language 2009 - 2009

Licenses & Certifications



Scrum Master Certified (SMC) - Scrum.org

500413

Skills

PHP • React.js • GraphQL • Mobile Applications • iOS development • Web Design • Project Management • Web Development • Web Applications • B2B eCommerce

Honors & Awards



1st place Start-up Weekend MEGA - Start-up Weekend

Jun 2014

project: "Cryonix Alternate Reality Game Platform."

Top 10 finalist - Wayra México

Jul 2013

project: "Nearbeats la Red Social de la Realidad Aumentada"